Daniel Duffy, Software Engineer

Denver, United States, 2144783812, dpd1208@gmail.com

LINKS	Portfolio, LinkedIn		
PROFILE	Experienced full stack software developer with a background in product ownership bringing a high level of quality and detail to everything I do. Always staying up to date with the latest technologies. Currently developin mainly in react and java within the Adobe Experience Management environment.		
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
Jul 2020 — Present	Software Engineer - React, AEM, Sli	ng TV (DISH Network)	Denver
	Developed and maintained a library of over 100 reusable react components in AEM used by content managers in our web application. Drove customer retention through reducing load times in the change subscription flow by over ten seconds. Implemented the current site-wide search solution leveraging Lucidworks framework. Contributed to the development and implementation of a java sports-finder service to promote customer acquisition during high profile events.		
Aug 2019 — Jun 2020	Software Engineer - Growth, Sling TV (DISH Network)		Denver
	Lead engineer for growth team responsible for implementation and delivery of customized, targeted experiences through Adobe Target. Pioneered complex development in the platform's Visual Experience Composer to enable quick prototyping and A/B testing in production outside of scheduled releases.		
Oct 2017 — Aug 2019	Product Owner, Sling TV (DISH Network)		Denver
	Managed the refinement and delivery of backlogs for multiple teams in an agile/scrum environment. Released improved cancellation flow and expanded its use to all lines of business. Facilitated re-architecture of acquisition flow through event storming, stakeholder and customer interviews, and strong collaboration with design teams in order to provide best-in-class customer experience.		
Jun 2015 — Jun 2017	Product Owner, Provident Funding	Assoc.	Denver
	Led the loan servicing division's transition from waterfall to agile development framework by training all parties involved in product life cycles, writing the policies for adherence to agile principles, and refining the existing backlog of over 300 projects based on divisional goals and priorities.		
EDUCATION			
Sep 2018 — Apr 2019	Coding Bootcamp Certificate , University of Denver		Denver
Sep 2008 — May 2012	BA Economics, University of Texas at Austin		Austin
	Degree in economics focusing in economic statistics. Minor in Latin with a certificate in European studies.		
SKILLS	React	MySQL	
	JavaScript	Java	
	CSS	Adobe Suite	
	Node.js	Agile Methodologies	
AWARDS AND RECOGNITION	Sling MVP Award	Denver	
	First recipient of Sling's Most Valuable Player award based on performance and outcomes.		
	Out at DISH Chapter Lead	Denver	

Elected representative of the downtown office Out at DISH employee resource group for LGBTQ+ individuals and allies.